NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
〜
&lrm;（アイコ）はっ…
（雄哉(ゆうや)）すまない
I'm sorry.
でも 分かっただろ
But now you know.
Your body is a fake.
君の体は偽物なんだ
偽物って… 何？
What do you mean by "fake"?
どういう意味？
What does that mean?
Your body is made of a special material
called artificial organisms.
その体は人工生体という
特殊な素材で作られている
Artificial organisms?
人工… 生体… って？
That's right.
（雄哉）そうだ
（篠山(しのやま)）
おいおい 荒っぽすぎやしないか
Hey, now.
Wasn't that a little rough?
（黒瀬(くろせ)）うむ
Young lady!
（篠山）お嬢さん
状況！
Heads up!
（アイコ）うわっ！
こいつが人工生体だ
That's artificial organisms.
I know that.
知ってます
My dad's company developed
artificial organisms.
だって お父さんの会社
人工生体の…
だったよね アイコちゃん
That's right, isn't it, Aiko?
（アイコ）あっ…
覚えてない？ 黒瀬
Remember me? I'm Kurose.
君の治療を担当した
由良(ゆら)と伊佐津(いさづ)と一緒にいた
I worked with your doctors,
Yura and Isazu.
あ…！
あっ…
Mr. Kurose! What is this all about?
黒瀬さん！
これ どういうことですか？
（黒瀬）まあ そこに掛けて
Please, take a seat.
ちょっと 込み入った話なんだが
It's a rather complicated story.
Try and stay calm while I tell it.
落ち着いて聞いてほしいんだ
あっ…
２年前の秋
Two years ago, in the fall,
交通事故で 君は重症を負った
you were injured in a car accident.
そのおかげで 長期の入院と
リハビリを強いられている
You had to endure
a long hospital stay and rehabilitation.
However, your injuries
were so severe then,
けれど
あのとき 君が受けたダメージは
実は 命を助けられないくらい
深刻なものだったんだ
that we weren't able to save your life.
あっ…
What?
えっ？
我々は君を救うために
In order to save you,
we decided to utilize a technology
that we had developed.
我々が生み出した
最新の技術を生かそうと考えた
You were the first person
this treatment was ever used on.
君に
世界で初めての治療法を用いたんだ
世界で… 初めての…？
The first person ever?
That's right.
（黒瀬）そうだ
We separated your brain from your body
君の脳と体を別々に切り離して
and treated each separately.
それぞれに適切な処置を施す
えっ？
However, if we simply separated them,
（黒瀬）
しかし 単に切り離したのでは
it'd be impossible to sustain
your body and brain.
脳も体も
自身を維持することができない
So, we created a duplicate body
using artificial organisms.
そこで 我々は
人工生体による
君の複製体を使うことにした
脳には 人工生体で作られた体を
We put your brain into the artificial body
and the artificial brain into your body
to keep you alive.
体には 人工生体の脳を
それぞれ組み合わせて
生命を維持する
The person named Aiko Tachibana
now has two existences.
（雄哉）橘(たちばな)アイコという人間が
２つの存在に作り直されたんだ
私が… ２人に…？
There are two of me?
When you were born,
橘アイコが誕生したとき
a copy of your body was made
using artificial organisms.
同時に人工生体によって
同じ肉体が作られていた
That's your duplicate.
それが複製体だ
What? You mean my clone?
えっ？ 私のクローン？
It's not a clone.
クローンではない
It's a body exactly like yours
that is made of artificial living cells.
人工の生体細胞によって作られた
本人と そっくりな体だ
なんで そんなもの…
Why was that made?
Your father's company
and Kiryu Research partnered
（黒瀬）君のお父さんの会社は
桐生(きりゅう)研との間で
社員の家族の複製体を作成する
実験提携契約を結んでいたんだ
in an experiment to construct
duplicates of employees
and their families.
（アイコ）あっ…
You had a checkup at Kiryu Research
every year on your birthday, right?
誕生日ごとに 桐生研に
定期健診を受けに行っていただろ
That was to compare you to the duplicate
あれは…
複製体が正常に育っているかを
比較確認するためのものだ
and confirm it was growing properly.
What? Are you serious?
（アイコ）何… それ…
Dad never told me that! Nobody did.
そんなの… お父さんも誰も…
And that surgery!
手術のことだって
Dr. Isazu never said anything!
伊佐津先生 何も言ってなかった！
桐生研の極秘技術だからね
It was top secret at Kiryu Research.
Such information could not be made public.
情報が一般に知られるわけには
いかなかったんだよ
でも お父さんから
聞いたことある！
But Dad told me
that even artificial organism technology
今の人工生体の技術じゃ
脳みそとか 丸ごとの人とか
作れないって！
can't create brains or whole bodies!
Only one person succeeded in doing that.
それを成功させた人間が
１人だけいた
（アイコ）あっ…
由良俊英(としひで)
Toshihide Yura.
Dr. Yura?
由良… 先生…
（アイコ）んっ！
（雄哉）
君の本当の体は あそこにある
Your real body is there.
ゲート？
At the Gate?
（雄哉）
そう あの門をくぐり
さかのぼった はるか先
Yes, it's through that gate,
far into the area beyond it.
あっ！ 爆心地？
What? At ground zero?
（雄哉）そうだ
Correct.
Ground zero, Primary Point.
爆心地…
プライマリー･ポイント
We can get your real body back
if we go there.
あそこに行けば
君の本当の体を取り戻せる
My real body.
私の… 本当の体…
（雄哉）
そして そこにはまだ生きている
They're still alive there, too...
your mother and little brother.
君のお母さんと弟君が
What?
えっ！
行けば 助けられるかもしれない
You might be able to save them.
どうして分かるの？ そんなこと
How can you possibly know that?
あっ…！
What is this?
何 これ…
They wore those clothes that day!
あの日 着てた服…
Their hair is growing.
髪が伸びてる…
（雄哉）
あの日から ずっと生きてるんだよ
They've been alive since that day.
It's up to you to believe it or not.
信じるか信じないかは 君次第だ
But you can only save
your mother and brother
だが お母さんと弟君を救うには
君をプライマリー･ポイントに
連れていく必要がある
by going to Primary Point.
（アイコ）あっ…
I want you to come with us.
俺たちと一緒に行ってほしい
But why would you go
to such a dangerous place
でも なんで
神崎(かんざき)君が私と家族のために
わざわざ
あんな危ない所に行くって言うの？
to help me and my family?
If you can get your real body back,
君が本物の体を取り戻せば
we can put an end to the Burst.
バーストを
終息させることができるからだ
What? End the Burst?
えっ バーストを？
Yuya Kanzaki kidnapped Aiko Tachibana?
（伊佐津）神崎雄哉が橘アイコを？
（竹原(たけはら)）はい
Yes, sir.
その 神崎ですが…
The school transfer paperwork
for this Kanzaki guy was forged.
転入書類が偽造だったとのこと
That person doesn't even exist.
おそらく該当する人物は
この世に存在しないと
２人は今 どこに？
Where are they now?
境界線地区のようです
In the Border Zone.
タウンか
The Town, huh?
（黒瀬）君も知ってのとおり
As you know,
２年前の秋に
桐生生命工学研 第二研究所で
two years ago, the abnormal
artificial cell proliferation occurred
at Kiryu Biotech Research Facility Two.
人工細胞の異常増殖
いわゆる“バースト”が起こった
It was known as the Burst.
The Malignant Matter that caused the Burst
バーストを起こした
マリグナント･マターは
spilled out of the facility,
第二研から あふれだし
峡谷伝えに
下流へと流れはじめた
and flowed downriver
through the valley.
The government immediately
upgraded the dams
政府は 急遽(きゅうきょ)
下流のダムをすべて改造し
into barriers to prevent the Matter
from advancing.
マターの流出を
防ぐための防壁にした
However, it overcame each barrier,
だが それらの防壁を乗り越えて
and has now reached
a point just before the Sea of Japan.
今や 日本海を
目前とする所まで迫っている
If it gets beyond Aimoto Dam,
the so-called Gate,
ゲートを呼ばれる愛本遮断堰(あいもとしゃだんぜき)を
もし 越えられれば
日本はもとより
it's impossible to imagine
the amount of damage
世界各地に及ぶ被害も
計り知ることができない
it would cause to Japan and the world.
I already know that!
そんなの 分かってます！
The trigger that caused the Burst
was the surgery
そのバースト発生の
引き金となったのが
that separated your mind and body.
君の体の分離手術だ
あっ…
私の… 手術… が？
My surgery caused it?
何 言って…
What are you saying?
You mean
だって…
I'm the cause of the Burst?
私がバーストの原因… なんて…
（黒瀬）落ち着いて
Don't worry.
君がじゃない
It wasn't you.
君に施された手術が だ
It was the surgery performed on you.
When your body and brain were separated,
分離された君の複製体が
your duplicate treated it as a crisis.
そのことを非常事態と認識して
It sent other artificial organisms
in the research facility's pool
研究所内にプールされていた
他の人工生体を異常増殖させたんだ
into abnormal cell proliferation.
そっ そんなの信じられるわけ…
You expect me to believe that?
Why are you trying to deceive me?
だまして どうするつもり？
ほっぺたが黒くなったのも
何か 仕掛けがあったんでしょ？
You used some kind of trick
to turn my cheek black, didn't you?
That video of Mom and Ryota could be...
お母さんと亮太(りょうた)の映像だって…
What?
何？
あっ…
見てて
Watch this.
はっ！
あっ… 文字？
Is that writing?
This is your body's serial number.
（雄哉）
これが その体の製造個体シリアル
あっ…
Please believe us.
（雄哉）信じてほしい
俺たちは 何としてでも
この災厄を終息させたい
We will do whatever it takes
to end this disaster.
We need your cooperation.
君の協力が必要なんだ
I know it is hard to accept this
（黒瀬）
まあ すぐ信じろって言っても
無理だと思うが
just because we ask you to.
It's gotta be a real shock.
（篠山）しっかし 驚きだな
Who knew such a thing could happen?
本当に こんな実例があるとは
That's why I hired you.
（黒瀬）だから あんたに頼んだ
Just like you requested,
I formed a skilled team.
（篠山）
依頼のとおり
腕の立つチームを見繕っといた
面通ししちゃ もらえんか？
Do you want to see them?
-Yuya.
-Yes?
（黒瀬）雄哉
（雄哉）ええ
（篠山）
連れてくのか？ お嬢ちゃんも
Are you going to take her along?
We can't leave her here alone.
（黒瀬）
１人にはしておけないからな
Wasn't there an extra pair
of shoes over here?
えっと 確か
予備の靴がこのへんに…
I got her shoes.
（雄哉）ああ 靴なら回収してきた
What? Then get them out...
（黒瀬）
あ？ 何だよ それ
なら さっさと…
（ガタガタッ）
Hey! This is the fifth floor!
（篠山）おい！ ここは５階
（アイコ）はっ！
（ドン！）
-Damn!
-She's adapted fast!
（黒瀬）おお〜
（雄哉）適応しすぎだろ！
Emergency backup needed in the Zone!
（篠山）
区域内緊急伝達 応援要請！
There is really something
strange about me!
（アイコ）やっぱり 何か変だ！
I can move now!
動けた！
（ダイバー）あ？ 何だ？
What was that?
（篠山）
現在 マル特保護対象が逃走中
Special custody subject at large!
識別 セーラー服の少女！
Young girl in school uniform!
Requesting assistance! I repeat.
協力されたし！ 繰り返す
マル特保護対象が逃走中
Special custody subject at large!
識別 セーラー服の少女！
Young girl in school uniform!
（アイコ）ハア ハア…
なんで こんなことに… うっ！
Why is this happening to me?
うっ…
Special custody subject found!
（ダイバー）マル特対象 確認！
ハア ハア…
Who is that?
（ざわめき）
You sneaky bitch!
（相模(さがみ)）相変わらず 汚(きたね)えな
（楓(かえで)）何のこと？
What's this about?
The Hinosawa Pharma lab!
（相模）日野沢(ひのさわ)ファーマのラボ
Never heard of it.
（楓）忘れた
Bullshit!
（一樹(かずき)）ふざけんなよ！
Fine! Like I said...
はいはいはい だから…
（店員）おまたせしやした〜
Here's your order!
（楓）おお〜！
Thank you for the...
いっただきま…
マズくなるから
早く どっか行けば？
Buzz off.
I'm trying to eat.
何を！
Why you...
（ドン！）
What the...
何だ？
（楓）ええ〜！
（相模）何？
How did she...
（楓）上から？
From above?
-Hey, you...
-Are you okay?
（遙香(はるか)）ちょ… あなた
（一樹）大丈夫？
はっ！
-Are you hurt?
-I'm sorry!
（一樹）ケガは？
（アイコ）ご… ごめんなさい！
（アイコ）出口 どこですか？
Where is the exit?
It's over here.
えっ？ こ… こっち
裏口がある
There's a back door.
-Thank you!
-Hey, what's wrong?
ありがとう！
ねえ どうしたの？
Wait! This way!
（一樹）ちょっと！ こっちだ
（男性）おい さっきの...
This is an emergency. I need your help.
緊急だ 協力してくれ
Shino?
（相模）しのさん
You're not a Diver, are you?
君 ダイバーじゃないよね？
Why are you in the Town?
なんで タウンに？
-Please help me!
-What?
（アイコ）お願い！
（一樹）え？
I want to get out of here!
ここから出たいの！
（一樹）じゃあ…
In that case,
あっちだ
go that way.
There you are.
見〜っけ！
（２人）あっ！
-There she is!
-Thank God!
（相模）いた！
（篠山）よかった
Calm down, honey.
嬢ちゃん おとなしく…
What do you think you're doing?
（白石(しらいし)）何してるの あなたたち！
Don't you dare treat a woman like that!
女の子に乱暴しない
Who are you?
何？
I'll introduce you.
紹介する
Huh?
（相模）え？
This is my buddy, Shiraishi.
俺のバディの白石だ
Nice to meet you.
よろしく
はあ？
（楓）任務… 完了？
Mission... complete?
I'm sorry we scared you.
（白石）
怖がらせて ごめんなさいね
I know it's hard for you
to accept it all so easily.
そんなに 簡単に
聞き入れられるわけないわよね
ただ この人たちが悪い人じゃない
ってことも分かってほしいの
But I want you to understand
that these are not bad people.
Can we have more time
to explain all this?
もう少し
説明の時間をもらえないか？
Please! I'm begging!
頼む このとおり！
俺らに直接 仕事を？
しのさんが？
You want us to work for you, Shino?
What is this about?
どういうこと？
I looked you up on the server.
（篠山）
サーバから のぞかせてもらった
両チームとも いい腕だ
Both your teams are solid.
That's our mission log!
（一同）あっ
（相模）俺らのミッションログ
えっ なんで？
Why do you have that?
機動力 判断力 行動力
Your agility, judgment, and energy levels
are all way off the charts.
特化技能も ぬきんでてる
Coming from you, that means a lot, Shino.
しのさんから
んなに言ってもらえるなんてよ
You have a good eye.
見る目あるじゃん！
So, what's the target?
で ターゲットは？
Kiryu Biotech Research Facility Two.
桐生生命工学研 第二研究所
Primary Point.
プライマリー･ポイント
-What?
（一同）えっ！
Ground Zero?
爆心地？
（篠山）
そう そこで ある重要な
オブジェクトを回収したい
Right. We're going to recover
something important from there.
そのために
それを手に入れる鍵を
To get it, we have to bring the key
that unlocks it to Primary Point.
プライマリー･ポイントまで
送り届けてほしい
No one's ever returned from Area Three,
and this is even deeper.
生還者ゼロのエリア３(スリー)の
さらに奥だぜ
誰が すき好んで行くんだよ
Who the hell would go there?
Don't tell me the key is...
その鍵っていうのは もしかして…
先ほど 確保したあの少女だ
That girl you captured earlier.
（一同）えっ
She's just a civilian!
一般人じゃねえか！
She'll never make it!
無理 無理 無理！
あの子 何者なんです？
Who the hell is that girl?
I can't tell you right now.
（篠山）現時点では明かせない
ハア…
（黒瀬）少し 休もう
Let's take a break.
（桐生）
どうやら セル･アセンブラ２(ツー)は
It appears that Cell Assembler Two
has performed the way I hoped it would.
私が望んだ機能を
満たしているようだ
As predicted, my body is aging properly.
この体は 想定どおり
正しく老化している
豊かな終(つい)を迎えられそうだ
I can have a very fulfilling death.
It's quite interesting.
面白いものだ
Although the physical body
moves toward death,
五体は
死に向かっているというのに
the mind intends
to continue living forever.
心は いつまでも
生きられるつもりでいる
Cell Assembler Two could make
eternal life possible.
（伊佐津）
セル･アセンブラ２は
無限の寿命を可能にする技術です
For the sake of Kiryu Research
and for all of humanity,
我ら桐生研の未来のためにも
いえ 人類のためにも
可能な限り
ご存命でいてくださらねば
I hope you live for as long as possible.
The future is created by new lives.
未来は 新しい命が紡ぐものだ
Artificial organisms have proven
that life can take a new form.
（伊佐津）人工生体は
命の新しいあり方を
示してくれました
ここから先は 君がやりたまえ
I want you to take over
development from here.
どうだね？ 柚葉(ゆずは)ちゃんの具合は
By the way, how is Yuzuha doing?
あっ…
My daughter is still in a coma.
娘は まだ眠っております
そうか…
I see.
If only Toshi were still here.
俊(とし)がいてくれれば…
あの子は
私が必ず目覚めさせます
I swear that I'll bring her back
to consciousness.
Toshihide Yura is
no longer alive after all.
由良俊英は
もう この世にいないのですから
You all know the Gate well,
also known as Aimoto Dam.
（篠山）
君たちには おなじみのゲート
すなわち 愛本遮断堰
ここを抜けて
エリア１(ワン)にダイブイン
You'll move through into Area One,
then bust through K1 into Area Two.
Ｋ１を突破し エリア２(ツー)へ
After gearing up
at Yanagawara Camp in Area Two,
エリア２の柳河原(やながわら)キャンプにて
物資と武装を補充ののち
you'll proceed similarly
through Areas Three, Four and Five
同様にエリア３ ４ ５(スリーフォーファイブ)を越え
to arrive at Primary Point,
Kiryu Biotech Research Facility Two.
プライマリー･ポイント
桐生生命工学研 第二研究所に
到達する
作戦途上で
マターを死滅させるのは無理だし
We won't be able to destroy
the Matter on this mission
その必要もない
and won't have to.
As long as we deliver her
to the target point,
彼女を目的地に
送り届けることさえできれば
we'll achieve our goal.
目的は果たせる
And we're doing that insanity
with so few people?
そんな大それたことを
この少人数で？
That's right.
そう
活性化するマターを
かいくぐりながら
To reach the target point while avoiding
the Matter as it transforms,
目的地まで走破するには
it's best that the team
be as small as possible.
参加メンバーは
少なければ少ないほど 望ましいの
少ないほど…
As small as possible?
I believe this mission
（篠山）おそらく この作戦は
私も含め 皆にとって
かつてない困難な任務になるだろう
will be the most difficult
any of us has ever attempted.
しかし…
However,
君たちなら
必ずや 成し遂げられる
I'm certain
you're the ones to pull it off.
（一同）うむ
Sure, I'm in!
（楓）いいよ　私 やる！
（相模）え？
It does sound pretty cool.
だって 面白そうじゃん
You're crazy.
お前…
You get how dangerous it is,
don't you, Kaede?
どれほど 危険なことか
分かってるのよね？ 楓
That's why I'm in.
だから 言ってる
（遙香）じゃあ 私も行く
Then, I'll go, too.
（２人）あっ！
Sagami?
（一樹）相模さん
You ready for this?
（相模）覚悟あんのか？
（一樹）うむ
We have no idea
what kind of Matter we'll run into.
どんなマターが待ち構えてるか
分からねえエリアだぞ
うむ
So, the Misawa-Seri team is
with us, right?
では 三沢(みさわ)･芹(せり)チームは
参加確定で問題ないな？
-You got it.
-Right.
（楓）おっす
（遙香）ええ
I've deposited advances
into your accounts.
今 ２人の口座に前金を振り込んだ
（楓）おっ…
（遙香）え…
-What?
-Wow!
（楓）ええっ？
（遙香）あっ！
仕事を成し遂げた際には
成功報酬も支払う
You'll get a completion bonus
once the job is done.
命の保証はできない代わりに
金の保証はする
I can't guarantee you'll live,
but I can guarantee you'll get paid.
フフッ
If we do make it back,
I think we can manage on this.
これだけあれば
もし死に損なっても
どうにだってなるもんね〜
Kaede!
楓！
ハハッ 面白(おもしれ)え
I like it!
You make a tempting offer.
よっぽど ワケありのようだ
フッ
Fine. We're in.
分かった 受けて立つよ
どのダイバーも
たどりつけなかった場所だ
No Diver has ever been there.
I want to see it with my own eyes.
この目で見ておきたい
I appreciate it.
（黒瀬）感謝する
You advances are paid, as well.
２人の口座にも入金した
Ah, there's just one thing I forgot.
（篠山）
おっと！ １つ言い忘れてた
（一樹）あっ
Like we said,
the fewer people the better.
人数は
少ないほうがいいと伝えたが
But when we enter Primary Point,
プライマリー･ポイントまで
雇いたいのは
we take only one team.
どちらか １チームだ
-What?
-Why?
（相模）はあ？
（楓）何 それ？
It's a competition.
コンペティションだ
よりふさわしいチームを
採用したい
We want to use the best team.
A competition?
We're risking our lives for this!
コンペだと？ 命 張らせておいて
エリア３までの工程で判断する
We'll decide based on
performances up to Area Three.
じゃあ 残りの成功報酬を
全額 受け取れるのは…
Well, then who gets the completion reward?
One of your two teams.
どちらか １チームだ
Evidence!
（ダイバーＡ）エビデンス！
（ダイバーＢ）
アルファセブンツー･オメガ！
Alpha 72 Omega!
-Any update?
-None!
（ダイバーＡ）更新は？
（ダイバーＢ）なかった！
（ダイバーＡ）
なら なんで 指定のバイアル
カートリッジが効かねえんだ
Then why isn't
the vial cartridge working?
うわ〜っ！
ひっ！
They're shaped like humans.
人… 型？
くそっ！ 弾が抜けちまう！
The shots are going right through!
おお〜っ！
YUYA KANZAKI
FINAL REPORT
Happy 18th Birthday, Yuzuha!
～
We have to evacuate!
（スタッフＡ）緊急退避します
（スタッフＢ）うわ〜！
-Okay, you're all set.
-Take off!
（研究員１）よし 大丈夫だ
（研究員２）離陸させろ
はっ…
Earlier,
（アイコ）さっき…
私に見せてくれた
お母さんと亮太の映像
you showed me a video of Mom and Ryota.
あれ ホントに本当なの？
Was that real?
Yes.
ああ
私 夢だとばっかり思ってた
I always thought it was just a dream.
ねえ…
So,
who exactly are you, Yuya Kanzaki?
神崎君 あなた… 何者？
すでに 君が知っていることが
俺のすべてだと思ってくれ
Everything you already know about me
is all there is to know.
I bet you're hungry.
I'll get some food.
腹 減っただろ？
食事を用意してくる
（相模）
…で そっちのお坊ちゃんは何だ？
So, who is that boy?
He's your guide beyond Area Three.
（篠山）エリア３より先の案内人
He's the only person who knows
how to use Aiko Tachibana
鍵である橘アイコの対となる
錠の開け方を知っている—
to open the lock she's the key to.
ただ一人の人間だ
Aiko Tachibana?
（相模）橘アイコ？
セーラー服の彼女ね
The girl in the school uniform?
（楓）ふ〜ん
So, her name is Aiko.
あの子 アイコっていうんだ
Are you sure he can protect her?
でも こんなヤツに命あずけんの？
You want us to escort him
safely up there, too, right?
つうか こいつも守って
連れてけって話だろ？
（雄哉）安心してください
Don't worry.
I will take you to Ground Zero.
俺が皆さんを爆心地まで
連れていきますから
There is something very important
that I have to do there.
俺には あの場所で
やらなきゃならない―
大事なことがあるんで
そりゃまた 豪儀なことで！
That'll be a sight to see!
（バチン）
（ガタッ！）
（黒瀬）何だ！
（相模）上か？
-What was that?
-Upstairs?
Tachibana!
（雄哉）橘！
（篠山）非常電源！
（白石）動かない！
-Backup power!
-No good!
Open the window!
（黒瀬）窓 開けて！
（ガタン）
雄哉！
Yuya!
あっ
They got her!
やられた！
〜
Subtitles by Brian Athey